# JOHN LONG

Software Developer

CONTACT DETAILS Phone: (573) 579-1666

Email: jlcomp45@gmail.com Github: github.com/JohnALong LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/john-a-long/

# PERSONAL PROFILE:

I came to NSS for a front end capstone demo and was hooked. 11 days later, I attended a 3 week jump start, and began a full stack bootcamp on Sept. 30th. After many years with one company, this journey has been both terrifying and exhilarating yet the greatest one I have ever had. I have always loved solving problems and learning new things. Software development has opened pathways for this that I could never have imagined.

## INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS:

## That's My Cue:

A single page web application built in ReactJS. A user will be able to not only view different styles of cue, but get the builder contact info, save examples of the builder's work, and make notes regarding build times and cost for a new cue purchase.

• https://github.com/JohnALong/Thats-my-Cue

#### StatLock:

Full stack application built with Python/Django. Users will be able to create a pool team, track skill level of players, view wins and losses for most recent 20 matches, see win %'s, and view possible lineups for their team.

• https://github.com/JohnALong/Thats-my-Cue

#### React-Journal

Revision of original Daily Journal project from the NSS curriculum redone in React. I wanted to explore how React worked and further my understanding of the platform.

https://github.com/JohnALong/journal-react

### **GROUP PROJECTS:**

Built CRUD functionality in tasks section of web application using React, React-Bootstrap and JSON server

• github.com/JohnALong/reactive-nutshell

Built terminal application using Python classes and interfaces

• github.com/JohnALong/keahua-arboretum-net-surfers

#### Built full stack application using Python/Django

• github.com/JohnALong/bangazon-workforce-mgt-purely-magic

#### Built full stack Python/Django/React online shopping app

- github.com/JohnALong/bangazon-client-virtual-magicians-1
- github.com/JohnALong/bangazon-api-virtual\_magicians

#### **EDUCATION**

## Nashville Software School, Certificate - March 2020

- HTML5
- React
- CSS
  React-Bootstrap
- JavaScript
- Python/Django

# INTERESTS AND HOBBIES:

- Golf Organized and ran golf tournament fundraiser for 10 years
- Pool Captain of team that competed for 9 ball National Championships in 2017 & 2018
- Reading

## TECHNICAL EDUCATION

# Nashville Software School

Sept 2019 - present

Full Stack Web Developer

- Immersive, full-time, six-month software development bootcamp focused on full stack (React/Python/Django) development fundamentals and problem solving
- Final half of program executed in a simulated company environment with Scrum methodology
- GitHub used for project management, source code version control, and collaboration
- JavaScript fundamentals using DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components
- Using React, HTML, CSS built browser-based single-page applications
- Hands on application of Object Oriented Programming fundamentals
- Group and individual projects reflecting real world team dynamics and problem solving
- Using Python to build command line applications

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### AT&T

Apr 2001 - Apr 2019

**Customer Service Representative** 

- First point of contact for customers to consult on service needs, install, order, or billing issues, and identified opportunities to upsell customers on additional company offerings
- Consistently met and exceeded monthly sales quotas and was in top 3 of over 300 Customer Services Representatives numerous times
- Partnered with peers and management to develop new strategies for sales/process improvement by: Helped develop a new call flow process to gain customer trust and created a one page check list for call handling to ensure call flow consistency
- Responsible for on-the-job training for new hires ensuring successful adoption in a dynamic, fast paced environment
- Implemented a cooperative relationship between employees and management that was critical in having an award winning call center.
- Designed and led a peer coaching initiative that was implemented company wide in all call centers

# **Communications Workers of America**

Jan 2009 - Oct 2019

Vice President Local 6316

- Elected 4 times as Vice-President CWA Local 6316 representing over 400 members to help protect "bargained for" rights of all members
- Primary liaison between members and management for contract or work issues between 4 departments representing 10 different employee job titles
- Responsible for reviewing, preparing, and meeting on grievances for all members
- Delegate to Southeast MO Central Labor Council